Guide to the Jay Carl Anderson Photographs and Papers UA.30.01.0084
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Durham and North Carolina, 3
  - Other North Carolina, 3.2
    - Stock Car Racing, 1979; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Stock Car Racing Roujemont, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - Other, North Carolina, 1979, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Mountains and Beaches, 1980, 1986; 35mm Color Slides (Box 9)
    - Assorted NC Images, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - NC Contact Sheets, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
- Other Locations and Topics, 4
  Includes images of people, events, and locations outside of North Carolina or for commercial use. Includes many images of politicians and political events both in and outside of North Carolina, including Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, Terry Sanford, Jesse Jackson, Walter Mondale, and George Wallace, among others, and events and people during the 1976, 1980, and 1984 Presidential Campaigns, including the 1976 Democratic National Convention. Also included are images of people, events, and locations outside of North Carolina, including many in New York City and state, Europe, and the Soviet Union, among others. Commercial work included images in Research Triangle Park as well as images in and outside of North Carolina. Also included in this series are images with unknown locations and topics.
  - Politicians, 4.1
    Includes images of North Carolina state and local politicians as well as politicians outside of North Carolina, and other celebrities. Many images relate to Presidential campaigns and inaugurations, including the inauguration of Jimmy Carter and the Presidential Campaign of 1976, including many of Terry Sanford, then President of Duke, George Wallace and others, as well as the 1976 Democratic National Convention. Also included are the Presidential Campaigns of 1980 and 1984, including candidates Jesse Jackson (and his 1984 visit to Duke) and Walter Mondale, and Presidents Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter, and Ronald Reagan. Other individuals include celebrity visitors to Duke University in the 1970s and 1980s, including Eric Clapton in concert, Clint Eastwood, Patty Hearst, and many others. Many of the negatives and prints in this series were grouped into labeled folders but do not include individual names or labels.
    - 1984 Democratic Presidential Candidates Mondale, Hart, Jackson, Ferraro, BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1976 July; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - George Wallace, 1976; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - George Wallace, 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Gerald Ford, circa 1975; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Gerald Ford, 1975-1976, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter, circa 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter Contact Sheets, circa 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Jesse Helms, 1980; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Jesse Jackson, 1984; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Jim Hunt, undated; 35mm Color Slides (Box 9)
    - Jimmy Carter, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - Jimmy Carter, undated; Color Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - Jimmy Carter, 1978; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
    - Jimmy Carter Inauguration, 1977; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Jimmy Carter Inauguration, 1977 January; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - President Carter Visit to England Press Book, 1977; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - President Carter Visit to England Press Book, 1977; Black and White Photographic Prints (Box 17)
      Images not taken by Jay Anderson.
    - President Carter Visit to England Press Book, 1977; Newsprint, document photocopies (Box 28)
    - John B. Anderson, 1980; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 17)
    - Juanita Kreps, 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Politicians, 1976, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Politicians, 1980, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Politicians, 1981, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Ronald Reagan, 1976, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Walter Mondale, 1984; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Walter Mondale, circa 1977; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - Celebrities, Politicians, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - VIPS: Entertainers, etc., undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
  - Locations Outside North Carolina, 4.2
    Includes images of locations and events in other parts of the United States as well as Europe and Asia. Includes many images of New York City and other locations in New York state; Mardi Gras in New Orleans, Louisiana; various locations across Europe and the Soviet Union; and others.
    - Europe, 1977; 2 folders; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Europe, 1977; 2 folders; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 19)
    - Europe, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
    - Florida, 1978, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Florida, 1978, 1981; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Georgia: Atlanta, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Japan, undated; Color Photographic Prints (Box 19)
    - Japan Color Orig. 1, 1986; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Japan Color Orig. 2, 1986; 2 folders; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Louisiana: Mardi Gras, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - New York City, 1979, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - New York City, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - New York City, 1979; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
    - New York City Contact Sheets, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 18)
    - New York: Clinton, 1975; 35mm BxW and 120 Roll Film Negatives (Box 4)
    - New York: Color, 1979-1985; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Pennsylvania: Philadelphia, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Washington, DC, 1975, 1978, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Washington, DC, 1978; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Washington, DC Contact Sheets, circa 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 19)
    - Assorted Locations Contact Sheets, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 19)
  - Commercial Work, 4.3
    Includes images of individuals, machinery, buildings, and items taken for commercial use. Subjects include buildings and people in Research Triangle Park and images taken specifically for the New York Times, as well as other topics.
    - Commercial, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Commercial Work, undated; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Commercial: NYT, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 19)
    - Commercial Work, undated; Color Photographic Prints (Box 19)
  - Various Topics and Unknown Locations, 4.4
    Includes images of interiors, people, symposium/panel events, outdoor scenes, and other subjects. Some negatives are labeled, some labels are unintelligible, and many are unlabeled.
    - Various topics, unknown locations, 1975-1976, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Various topics, unknown locations, 1978-1990, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Various topics, unknown locations, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Various topics, unknown locations, undated; 35mm BxW Negatives (Box 4)
    - Unknown Locations, Various Topics, undated; 35mm Color Slides (Box 10)
    - Notes, contact sheets, slides, on various topics, 1978, undated; BxW contact sheets, 35mm color slides, 35mm color film negatives, 35mm color film transparency (Box 19)
    - Unknown Locations, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
    - Unknown Locations, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
- Exhibitions, Publications, and Writings, 5
  Includes images from other series that were printed and prepared for exhbitions in various locations, publications including Jay Anderson's photographs or related to his work and subjects in some way, writings and materials from his time as a Duke student that include or are related to his photography, to Duke University, or to Durham, and travel materials from his trip to Europe and the Soviet Union in 1977.
  - Prints for Exhibitions, 5.1
    Includes photographic prints made for display in exhibitions or submitted for awards or exhibitions. Many prints are mounted onto boards or printed at sizes larger than 8x10". Photographs in this series are included in other series, particularly Series 1.1 Campus, Series 1.3 Chanticleer, Series 2.1 Basketball, Series 3 Durham and North Carolina, and Series 4.1 Politicians. A very few items in this subseries include information about the event, exhibition, or contest for which they were prepared.
    - Prints for exhibition, circa 1974-1978; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 19)
    - Prints for exhibition, circa 1976-1977; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 20)
    - Mounted Print of Ronald Reagan and Jesse Helms, 1976, 1980; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 23)
    - East Campus Show 8x10" Mounted on 16x20", 11x14" (1 of 2), 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 24)
    - East Campus Show 8x10" Mounted on 16x20", 11x14" (2 of 2), 1976; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 25)
    - Mounted Prints, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 26)
    - Mounted High School Art, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 27)
    - Basketball, Water Lilies, undated; BxW Photographic Prints (Box 29)
  - Publications, 5.2
    Includes copies of publications featuring Jay Anderson’s work, as well as correspondence related to publishing his work and some additional publications that do not include Anderson’s work. Included are newspaper and magazine clippings from Duke and Research Triangle publications as well as the New York Times, correspondence with editors and managers at publications including the New York Times and Sports Monday, photocopies of images and works published in books and other media, and Duke photography publications Latent Image and The Archive. Latent Image number 5 (1980) includes two of Jay Anderson’s photographs; also included in this series are several other issues of Latent Image.
    - Publication Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 21)
    - Commercial Publications, 1980-1994 (Box 21)
    - Latent Image 1-4, undated (Box 21)
    - Latent Image 5, 6, 9, 12, undated (Box 21)
    - Latent Image 14-15, the Archive v. 86 no. 2, undated (Box 21)
    - Calendar, Brochure, Print Sample, Certificate, Notes, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1985-1987 (Box 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1982 (Box 28)
    - The Chronicle and The Summer Chronicle, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Photocopies, 1976-1989 (Box 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1985 (Box 28)
    - Basketball Photocopies as Booklet, 1978 (Box 28)
  - Writings, 5.3
    Includes papers and projects from Jay Anderson’s time as a student at Duke, including papers on the decline of student activism at Duke, working in Durham, commuting from West to East Campus, and the portrayal of presidential authority in the Chanticleer.
    - HIST 1665.01 Project, circa 1976 (Box 20)
    - "The Portrayal of Presidential Authority in the Chanticleer 1912-1977" (1 of 3), 1978; Paper and BxW Photographic Prints (Box 20)
    - "The Portrayal of Presidential Authority in the Chanticleer 1912-1977" (2 of 3), 1978; Paper and BxW Photographic Prints (Box 20)
    - "The Portrayal of Presidential Authority in the Chanticleer 1912-1977" (3 of 3), 1978; Paper and BxW Photographic Prints (Box 20)
    - Student Papers, 1974, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Baldwin Federation Emblem Entry, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Travel Materials, 5.4
    Includes tickets, maps, postcards, and memorabilia from Jay Anderson's travels around Europe (including England, France, Greece, the Netherlands, and other countries) and the Soviet Union in 1977.
    - Europe, 1977 (Box 21)
    - Europe, 1977; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - USSR, 1977; 3 folders (Box 22)
    - USSR: Russian Pronunciation, circa 1977; 33 1/3 Phonographic Disc (Box 22, Folder UA30010006-PD-0001)